Guide to the photograph album "Impressions of Iraq" compiled by L. Wells of RAF Hinaidi AD.MC.045
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- From top left clockwise: a portait of woman, a portrait of a Persian man, a portrait of a woman with a child, a Kurdish tribesman, and people participating in the Muharram Festival., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref27; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Women; Children; Men; Crowds; Religious Holiday; Southern Kurdistan, Iraq; Iraq; Head Covers/Veils; Individual Portraits; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- A portrait of a man with his cattle., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref28; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Men; Cattle/Cows; Animals; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; English Writing
- From top left clockwise: a group portrait of four children, a street in Al Ashar, photographs of Korah Creek, and a mosque., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref29; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Basra, Iraq; Streets/Roads; Rivers; Children; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Mosques; English Writing
- A portrait of a man with his cattle pulling a water cart., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref30; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Cattle/Cows; Men; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Iraq; English Writing
- From top left clockwise: a shepherd, an RAF hospital in Basra, a mosque in Basra, a mosque in Az Zubayr, and the junction of the Tigris and Euphrates Rivers., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref31; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Hospitals; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Mosques; Basra, Iraq; Men; Children; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Rivers; Shepherds; Animals; Head Covers/Veils; English Writing
- A group portrait of two men in a "guffa.", Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref32; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Men; Head Covers/Veils; Group Portraits; Boats/Ships; Water; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Iraq
- From top left clockwise: a mosque in Az Zubayr, the entrance to Ezra's Tomb, fishermen in the Hammar Lakes, a souk, an RAF hospital in Basra, and a wharf., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref33; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Men; Children; Group Portraits; Hospitals; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Basra, Iraq; Lakes; Fishing; Markets; Mosques; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Religious Sites; Basra, Iraq; Az-Zubayr, Basrah, Iraq
- A gang of water buffalo swimming., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref34; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Animals; Rivers; Photographic Prints; Iraq; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing
- From top left clockwise: a memorial for the North Lancaster Regiment, a port on the Tigris River, a date palm, the Temple of Ishtar, the Temple of Marduk, and the Tomb of Daniel., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref35; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Rivers; Ports; Palm Trees; Military/Soldiers; Temples; Iraq; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Religious Sites; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Tigris River
- A dog nursing its pups., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref36; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Dogs; Animals; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; English Writing
- From top left clockwise: a portrait of a man holding a gun, a group of storks, lightning, and various nautical scenes in Hillah, Iraq., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref37; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Military/Soldiers; Men; Individual Portraits; Guns; Birds; Animals; Iraq; Boats/Ships; Ports; Rivers; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; English Writing; Uniforms; Hillah/al-Ḥillah, Iraq
- A group portrait of two men in their shop, one is working with a sewing machine., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref38; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Group Portraits; Sewing; Men; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq; Head Covers/Veils; Photographic Prints; English Writing
- Various views of the interior and exterior of the RAF hospital in Hinaidi, Iraq., 1930; AD_MC_045_ref39; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Rivers; Royal Air Force; Hospitals; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq
- A group portrait of the RAF Hinaidi hospital staff., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref40; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Men; Women; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Royal Air Force; Military/Soldiers; Nurses; Doctors; Iraq; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Uniforms
- A list of names for the preceding group portrait of the RAF Hinaidi hospital staff (ref 040)., 1930; AD_MC_045_ref41; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  English Writing
- Top left clockwise: The Officer's ward at RAF Hinaidi, the laboratory staff (Les Wells on right), bacteriological department, three servicemen standing in front of a sign for Iskandriyah with the caption 'En route to Babylon' (Les Wells left), servicemen sitting around a billet with decorations strung to the ceiling, three servicemen standing in front of a train (Les Wells left), pathological room at RAF Hinaidi., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref42; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Hospitals; Uniforms; Laboratories; Arabic Writing; English Writing; Iraq; Men; Tea/Coffee; Scientific Equipment; Horses; Animals
- An interior view of the Mannock Ward in an RAF hospital., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref43; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Men; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Hospitals; Group Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Iraq; English Writing
- Seven portraits of servicemen engaging in activities, including football and playing instruments., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref44; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Men; Animals; Group Portraits; Sports; Guns; Marching Band; Musical Instruments; Individual Portraits; Football; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Iraq; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Men; Costumes
- An aerial view of a Vickers Victoria plane over "Cheapside" RAF Hinaidi, Iraq., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref45; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Airplanes; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Transportation
- From top left clockwise: a group portrait of the RAF Hinaidi Hospital Blue Star Band (Les Wells second from left), a group portrait of the RAF hospital cricket team (Les Wells far left), a group portrait of the RAF hockey team (Les Wells bottom right), and a group portrait of the RAF hospital football team., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref46; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Men; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Group Portraits; Sports; Football; Uniforms; Musical Instruments; Gelatin Silver Prints; English language; Photographic Prints; Awards; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Tuxedos
- A fleet of biplanes flying over Iraq, captioned "Guardians of Iraq"., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref47; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Airplanes; Iraq; Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Gelatin Silver Prints; English Writing; Transportation; Rivers
- Seven group portraits of servicemen and servicewomen in their quarters, visiting monuments, or posing for sports team photos at RAF Hinaidi, Babylon (Hillah) and the Alwiyah Club., 1929 and 1930; AD_MC_045_ref48; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Sports; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Hospitals; Uniforms; Nurses; Men; Women; Group Portraits; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Iraq; English Writing; Hillah/al-Ḥillah, Iraq; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Christmas; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Doctors
- A fleet of biplanes., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref49; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Airplanes; Iraq; English language; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Transportation
- Top left clockwise: two images of Les Wells in the RAF Hinaidi laboratory, a group portrait of servicemen eating melon, a serviceman outside the RAF laboratory, a group portrait at a concert party., 1929; AD_MC_045_ref50; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Men; Women; Group Portraits; Costumes; Parties; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Hospitals; Laboratories; Food; Individual Portraits; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Iraq; English Writing; Parties; Scientific Equipment
- A silhouette of a person riding a camel., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref51; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  Camels; Animals; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Iraq
- The 1929 and 1930 menus for the RAF hospital and the Army Dental Corps in Hinaidi Iraq. L. Wells' name is listed in each., AD_MC_045_ref52; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)
  English Writing; Hinaidi, Kanun, Baghdad, Iraq; Military/Soldiers; Royal Air Force; Printed Materials
- The back cover of the album., Circa 1929 - 1930; AD_MC_045_ref53; Wells, Les, Active 1929 - 1939; 1 Photographic Prints (Box AD_MC_045)